Guide to the Jane Lathrop Stanford Papers SC0033B
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Jane Lathrop Stanford papers
1860-1975
1860-1905
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford, Jane Lathrop
SC0033B
14 Linear Feet
Scope and Content
The papers of Jane L. Stanford pertain largely to the founding and administration of Stanford University, along with her personal and social affairs; included in the papers are correspondence, business records, legal and financial papers, speeches, newsclippings, and biographical materials.
Biography
Jane Eliza Lathrop was born August 25, 1828, the daughter of Dyer Lathrop of Albany, New York. In 1850 she married Leland Stanford, returning with him to California in 1855 where they settled in Sacramento. Leland Stanford later became President of the Southern Pacific Railroad and Governor of California. Their only child, Leland Stanford, Jr., was born in 1868. During a European tour in 1884 he contracted typhoid fever and died in Florence, Italy. In 1885, Jane and Leland Stanford founded the Leland Stanford Junior University, in memory of their son. Jane was a full partner with her husband in the planning of the University, which opened in the fall of 1891. After her husband's death in 1893, she overcame great financial hardships to keep the University open until her husband's estate was settled. Thereafter, she directed expansion of the campus. She died on February 28, 1905 in Honolulu, Hawaii.
Provenance
Gifts of Jane Lathrop Stanford, Thomas Welton Stanford, David Starr Jordan, Helen Stanford Canfield, David H. Canfield, and others; also includes purchases.
Access Restrictions
The materials are open for research use.
Stanford University -- Administration.; Palo Alto (Calif.) -- History.; Claims against decedents' estates.; Universities and colleges -- Administration.; Vina Ranch (Calif.); Executors and administrators.; Railroads -- Management.; Stanford, Jane Lathrop; Palo Alto Stock Farm (Stanford, Calif.); Leib, Samuel Franklin; Stanford, Charles Villiers; Jenkins, Oliver Peebles,, Mrs.; Crothers, George E. (George Edward); Pacific Improvement Company; Stanford University. Memorial Church; Smith, Nicholas T.; Jordan, David Starr; Stanford, Jane Lathrop; Day, Clinton.; Cesnola, Luigi Parma di; Ross, Edward Alsworth, 1866-1951; Lathrop family.; Stanford, Josiah Winslow; Crocker, Charles Frederick.; Newton, Heber.; Stanford, Jane Lathrop; Sloss, Leon.; Shields, Daniel.; Lathrop, Ariel.; Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell), 1820-1906; Stanford University. Cantor Arts Center; Lathrop, Jane Ann Shields.; Lathrop, Dyer,; Nash, Herbert C.; Southern Pacific Company; Stanford Alumni Association; Lathrop, Charles G. (Charles G; Stanford University. Japanese Students Association; Stanford, Thomas Welton; Gurke Ranch (Calif.); Stanford, Leland; Shepley, Rutan and Coolidge.; Stanford University. Faculty Club; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Hopkins, Timothy; Taylor, Edward Robeson,; Harrison, Benjamin; Suzzallo, Henry,; Stanford University. Libraries; Jordan, Jessie Knight; Stanford, Helen M.; Stanford, Gertrude.
- Correspondence, 1868-1905; Series 1; 6 Linear Feet
  Series Description
  Outgoing correspondence dates from 1860 to 1905 and incoming correspondence, from 1871 to 1905. Most of the correspondence concerns the University. Other topics include personal and social matters, her travels, religious discussions, and her interest in kindergartens. Correspondents include David Starr Jordan, the first president of Stanford University, Charles Lathrop, Susan B. Anthony, Timothy and May Hopkins, Julia D. Grant (Mrs. Ulysses Grant) and other members of the Grant family, Caroline Harrison (Mrs. Benjamin Harrison), and Andrew D. White. There are also a large number of condolence letters on the death of Leland Stanford and of begging letters.
  - Outgoing, 1860-1905
    - 1860-1869 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - ALS to Leland Stanford. In San Francisco, baby's vaccination, small pox, personal news, 1868 or 1869
    - 1870-1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - to Mr. Scupham: regarding a piece of statuary, 1876 Nov 2
    - 1880 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - ANS card "Jennie to Leland" [not in Jane's handwriting], 1880 June 17
      - ALS to Leland. Berlin, Leland Jr. ill, great Continental route (RR). "I have on heavy red woolen drawers and shirt..." (2 pp), 1880 Nov 8
      - ALS to Leland. Antwerp art works, Rochfort ? (2 pp), 1880 Nov 14
      - ALS to Leland. Brussels (2 pp), 1880 Nov 17
    - 1881 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - ALS to Leland. Naples. Presented to Pope, assassination of Czar (3 pp), 1881 Mar 16
      - ALS to Leland. Bought a statue (3 pp), 1881 Mar 24
      - ALS to Leland. Rome. Activities of Leland Jr., plans for rest of trip (2 pp), 1881 Mar 28
    - 1884 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - ALS. J. L. Stanford to Timothy and May Hopkins - Leland Jr.'s illness, typhoid fever, 1884, Feb 25
      - Tel. Leland and J.L.Stanford to Mrs. Mark Hopkins - death of Leland, Jr., 1884 Mar 13
      - ALS. J. L. Stanford to Mrs. May Hopkins - thanking her for her kindnesses; love of Palo Alto home, 1884, Apr 20
    - 1886 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - ALS to May and Tim Hopkins. Acknowledging Christmas remembrance, 1886 Jan 2
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Memories of Menlo Park; sister still with her; Mr. Stanford and his senatorial duties, 1886 Jan 29
      - LS to W. T. Ross. Book on voice culture promised to Leland Jr., 1886 May 24
    - 1887 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - ALS to Timothy and May Hopkins re: Mrs. Mark Hopkins; death of Mrs. Fred Crocker; longs for Palo Alto; anxiety concerning Mr. Stanford, 1887 Feb 21
      - ALS to Timothy and May Hopkins. Acknowledges flowers, 1887 Mar 27
      - tel from Leland and Jane to Timothy Hopkins. Congratulations on birth of daughter, 1887 Mar 28
      - tel to Timothy Hopkins. Congratulations on birth of daughter, 1887 Mar 29
      - ALS to Timothy Hopkins. Wants him to accompany her to Hattie Crocker's wedding, 1887 May
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Regrets she cannot accept luncheon invitation; wants to meet Mrs. Parks, 1887 Aug 6
      - L to Mrs. Weatherbee. Receiving callers Monday evening, 1887 Nov 20
    - 1888 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - LS to Mrs. Cooper. Received letter from Susan B. Anthony [photocopy], 1888 Jan 19
      - AL to Susan B. Anthony. Is sending check [photocopy], 1888 Mar 6
      - ALS J. L. Stanford to May Hopkins - death of Charles Crocker., 1888 Aug 17
      - ALS to Mrs. Cooper. Admiration for her work [photocopy], 1888 Nov 20
      - ALS to Mrs. Cooper. Arranged RR passes [photocopy], 1888 Nov 28
      - ALS to Mrs. Cooper. Concerned that she is working too hard [photocopy], 1888 Dec 7
    - 1889 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Acknowledges photograph of Mrs. Hopkins and baby; Mr. Flood's poor health; remembrance to Mrs. Park; Mr. Nash's continued improvement [J. L. Stanford incorrectly dated first page as March 22], 1889 Jan 22
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Acknowledges flowers, 1889 Apr 22
      - ALS to May Hopkins and Mrs. Park. Regrets she was unable to see them; yesterday was her son's 21st birthday, 1889 May 15
      - ALS to Timothy Hopkins. Concerned over Mrs. Hopkins' health, 1889 Nov 18
    - 1890 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - ALS (press copy) to Mr. Gage re. museum plans, 1890 Jan 2
      - ANS to May Hopkins. Sends a doll and outfit for Lydia, 1890 Mar 8
      - ALS to Mrs. Cooper. Writes of her religious reading [photocopy], 1890 Mar 9
      - ALS to Susan M. Harvey. On reception given the Stanfords in Sacramento, 1890 May 4
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Acknowledges photo of Lydia; anticipated trip to Europe, 1890 May 19
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Floral decorations in stateroom; Mr. Stanford taking the cure at Kissingen, also Gov. Low, 1890 July 4
      - ALS to Susan M. Harvey, 1890 Nov 19
      - ALS to Mrs. Cooper. Sends check for $300 [photocopy], 1890 Nov 25
      - ALS to Mrs. Cooper [photocopy], 1890 Nov 28
      - ALS to Timothy and May Hopkins. Acknowledges flowers; illness of Dora Miller and her mother, 1890 Dec 6
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Anxious about Mrs. Hopkins' health; visit to Montreal; call from Mr. Pixley; Mr. Nash holding his own, [1890]
    - 1891 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Invites Mrs. Hopkins and Mrs. Park to luncheon., May 5, 1891
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Their feelings for May and Timothy; thoughts on religious faith, June 12, 1891
      - to Timothy and May Hopkins. Welcome home., Aug 11, 1891
      - L to Mrs. Upson. [photocopy], 4-Nov
      - ALS to May Hopkins. re decorative screens she needs for Washington house, 1891 Nov 16
      - ALS to May Hopkins. seasonal greetings; climate in Washington and their health, 1891 Dec 23
    - 1892 Jan-Jun (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - ALS to Timothy and May Hopkins. At N.Y. so that Mr. Stanford may attend sale of horses. Called on Hattie Alexander. Della Clements wants indemnification for the killing of her father on the R.R., Jan 24, 1892
      - ALS to Timothy and May Hopkins. Glad of bequest by Moses Hopkins. Anxious regarding sister. Mr. Stanford in N.Y. to attend railroad meeting. Wants' Timothy's suit to begin., Feb 19, 1892
      - ALS to Timothy and May Hopkins. Thankful Timothy's suit was settled out of court. Greatly relieved regarding sister. Approaching visit to Europe., March 10, 1892
      - ALS to Timothy Hopkins. Acknowledging flowers. Age brings sorrow., June 9, 1892
      - ALS to Timothy and May Hopkins. Mr. Nash has a hemorrhage., June 10, 1892
      - ALS to Mrs. D. S. Jordan. Sister's illness, Mr. Nash's illness, love of Palo Alto., June 16
      - ALS to Timothy and May Hopkins. Mr. Stanford at Aix les Bains. Anxiety as to his health. Death of Samuel Wilson., June 22, 1892
    - 1892 Jul-Oct (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - ALS to Timothy Hopkins. Wants to secure staterooms for October. Proposed visit to Switzerland. Glad Mr. Nash is improving. Receives bad news from sister., July 6, 1892
      - ALS to Timothy Hopkins. Is not well and has had doctor. Surprised that her brother and Mr. Nash are still in London., July 18, 1892
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Acknowledging body muff., Oct 4, 1892
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Regarding Capt. Berryman., Oct 5, 1892
      - ALS to Timothy and May Hopkins. Acknowledging fruit and flowers. Fearful that pre-election strain will undo the summer's gain for Mr. Stanford. Mr. Hopkins must be glad he is free of 4th and Townsend St. Has her niece Jenny with her., Oct 30, 1892
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Wants to learn of a good nurse., 1892
    - 1893 Jan-Jun (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - L to John A. Logan, Jr., (written by Jane's secretary), 1893 Jan 30
      - LS to Mrs. Hubbard. re memorial for her sister (Mrs. Anna Hewes?) prepared by D.A.R., 1893 Jan 31
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Mr. Stanford is better. Had a good letter from C.P. Huntington. Wants Mrs. Hopkins to do some shopping in London. Wants to have Jennie Lathrop for always., 1893 March 31, 1893
      - ALS to Susan M. Harvey. Mr. Stanford gaining, 1893 June 3
      - ALS to Timothy and May Hopkins. Thankful they are back on American soil. Mr. Stanford much improved. Plans for the Museum., 1893 June 12, 1893
    - 1893 Jul-Dec (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - ALS to Susan M. Harvey. Death of Mr. Stanford, 1893 July 15
      - LS and cover to J. Jordan, Leland Stanford Div. 283 B. of L. E. In appreciation of their momento, 1893 July 25
      - ALS to Charly [Lathrop] on paying bills [and transcription], 1893 Aug 23
      - ALS to Susan M. Harvey. Thanks for her letters; her grief and resolve to advance Leland's work, 1893 Nov 24
      - ALS to Timothy Hopkins. Acknowledging gift of mummy cloths to the Museum., 1893 Dec 5, 1893
      - ANS to Ethel Ingalls, 1893 Dec 26
      - ANS to Timothy and May Hopkins. Acknowledging Christmas gift., 1893 Dec 26
      - ALS (copy). J. L. Stanford to Bishop and Mrs. Newman re. her grief over death of Leland Stanford., 1893, undated
    - 1894 Jan-Jul (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - A.N.S. "Edward for Mrs. Stanford" to Mr. Ferguson re: bills to be paid., Jan 6, 1894
      - ALS to Susan M. Harvey. "Thanks for you kind thought of me", Jan 8, 1894
      - ALS to Timothy Hopkins. Hopes that May will come safely through her ordeal., Feb 3, 1894
      - ALS to John F. Lewis. Requests John F. Lewis to take charge of Vina distillery, warehouse, and Brandy Dept. during Guptills leave of absence. Distillery to be shut down., June 20, 1894
      - ALS to Senator C. K. Davis. Thanks for note and expressions concerning Leland Stanford., July 21, 1894
      - ALS to Senator James L. Pugh. Telegram urging passage of bill., July 23, 1894
      - ALS [and typed and signed copy] to C.P. Huntington. Not assigning power of attorney to anyone., July 27, 1894
    - 1894 Sep-Dec (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Two [2] TLS to C.P. Huntington, Stillman and Hubbard, and Chas. F. Crocker, loan Speyer and Co., obligations of Pacific Improvement Co., Sep 14, 1894
      - ALS to [John F.] Lewis. Tells him to sell no more wines by small quantities especially to people around Palo Alto proper., Sep 23, 1894
      - TL to Justice Stephen J. Field. Re. Field's resignation from the board of Trustees., Oct 27, 1894
      - ALS to May and Timothy Hopkins. Suit over Hopkins' inheritance, Mrs. Hopkins-Searls., 1894 Nov
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Acknowledges flowers. Is not well. Returning via Canadian Pacific., Dec 16, 1894
      - Tel. [written copy] to T.H. Hubbard. Mexican International RR, [1894?]
    - 1895 Jan-Apr (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Acknowledging photo case. Affairs at Menlo. Mr. Nash at Santa Barbara., Jan 12, 1895
      - ALS to Russell J. Wilson. Wants the Carpentier obligation arranged., Feb 18, 1895
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Endorses The Raymond. Mr. Nash improving. Mr. Stanford's birthday., March 3, 1895
      - ALS to Senator and Mrs. Thurston. Arranging for visit to Palo Alto., March 19, 1895
      - ALS to David S. Jordan. Introducing Senator Thurston., March 19, 1895
      - ALS to George A. Knight. Acknowledges receipt of resolution adopted by Republican State Convention. Only aim in life is to secure future of University., March 23, 1895
      - ALS to James G. Chelsey. Thanks for penning resolution., March 23, 1895
      - ALS to R. J. Wilson. Struggle to maintain the University., March 30, 1895
      - ALS to Russell J. Wilson. Condition on which she will vote for Huntington as president of S.P. Co., April 4, 1895
      - ALS to Chas. Webb Howard, Pres. Spring Valley Water Works. Business., April 9, 1895
      - ALS to N. K. Masten. Will not sign obligations made without consulting her., April 10, 1895
      - ALS to Wilson and Wilson. Will accept no assistance from SlP. Co. or P.I. Co. in government suit., April 16, 1895
      - ALS to Charles W. Howard. [2 handwritten copies] Wants the blow pipe opened., April 23, 1895
      - TLS to Russell J. Wilson. To hasten progress of government suit. Enclosure: Attorney General to L.D. McKisick., April 30, 1895
    - 1895 May - June (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - ALS to Russell J. Wilson. To expedite government suit., May 1, 1895
      - ALS to Joseph H. Choate. Wants an appointment., May 1, 1895
      - ALS to Thomas H. Hubbard. Explains lack of response to inquiries., May 5, 1895
      - ALS to President Grover Cleveland. [original copy and 2 photostat copies] Gratitude for aid in expediting government suit., May 9, 1895
      - ALS to Richard M. Olney. Grateful for expediting government suit., May 9, 1895
      - ANS to Thomas H. Hubbard. Letter from Hubbard not received at Albany., May 9, 1895
      - ALS to Gov. James H. Budd. Thanks for cheering words., May 15, 1895
      - photostat of ALS to Jas. D. Lynch. Unable to aid with proposed biographical sketch of L. Stanford, May 16,1895
      - ALS to Stillman and Hubbard. Notes signed., May 23, 1895
      - ALS to A. W. Manning. Has ordered librarian to accept gift of Swedenborg's Works., May 31, 1895
      - ALS to Richard Olney. Congratulations that he is Secretary of State and regrets that he leaves Department of Justice., June 8, 1895
      - ALS to Russell J. Wilson. Will keep within easy reach., June 27, 1895
      - ALS to Stillman and Hubbard. Refuses to sign note for funds to pay interest., June 28, 1895
      - to Judge E. M. Ross. Grateful for his righteous decision., June 1895
    - 1895 Jul-Aug (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - ALS to Col. C. F. Crocker. Acknowledges Crocker as husband's best associate and closest friend., July 2, 1895
      - ALS (original and 2 photostats) to John Garber. Thanks for help in government suit., July 6, 1895
      - ALS to John F. Sheehan. Feels uplifted by his letter. Has heard of his son., July 6, 1895
      - ALS to Edward R. Taylor. Thanks for his assistance to Judge Garber. Favorable decision lifts clouds from Stanford name., July 6, 1895
      - ALS to George H. Gray. Thanks for his interest and aid on suit., July 6, 1895
      - ALS to Morrill Goddard. Appreciates his offer of the columns of the N.Y. World., July 30, 1895
      - ALS (2 photocopies) to Andrew White., Aug 9, 1895
      - TLS to C. P. Huntington. Selling of bonds., Aug 30, 1895
    - 1895 Sep-Dec (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - ALS (photocopy) to George L. Burr. Letter of thanks., Sep 17, 1895
      - ALS to Mr. and Mrs. Chas. Holbrook. Regrets she cannot attend wedding of their daughter., Sep 25, 1895
      - ALS to Timothy Hopkins. Gratitude for evidences of his kindly regard., Sep 27, 1895
      - ALS to C. P. Huntington. He may make appointment for tomorrow., Oct 6, 1895
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Acknowledges candy. In Washington with Mrs. Grant., Oct 1895
      - ALS (photocopy) to Andrew White. Reason for going to California., Nov 5, 1895
      - ALS to H.D. Sheldon. Thanks for telegram from Associated Students., Nov 5, 1895
      - AL to Susan B. Anthony. Appreciation of her friendship [photocopy - missing final page], No 9, 1895
      - ALS to May Hopkins. Charms of the Berkshire Inn. Roses from Searls. Tea with Mrs. Cass. Visits Berkshire cemetery., Dec 7, 1895
      - ALS to Stillman and Hubbard. Declines to increase liabilities of P.I. Co., Dec 23, 1895
      - ALS (telegram) to Timothy and May Hopkins. Good wishes for the New Year., Dec 31, 1895
      - ALS (telegram) to Russell Wilson. Why the government suit delayed., undated 1895
    - 1896 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - TL to Timothy and May Hopkins. Acknowledges Christmas gift., Jan 22, 1896
      - ALS to [Thomas H.] Hubbard. Contracts for new work., Jan 23, 1896
      - ALS to Joseph H. Choate. Has engaged attorney to draw will. Thinks estate will amount to much less than figure named by Mr. Choate., Feb 21, 1896
    - 1896 Mar 1-Mar 5 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Scope and Contents note
      The following are all letters and telegrams acknowledging support and congratulatory notes received on winning government suit except where otherwise noted.
      Mar. 2, 1896 to Justice Fuller and all associate Justices, David S. Jordan, Kappa Kappa Gamma, John R. McLean, Louis Sloss, Stanford Students.
      Mar. 3, 1896 to Clinton Catherwood; Joseph H. Choate; A.L. Clark; George Crocker; P.L. Crovat; C.H. Cummings; A.B. Farquhar; George Goodman; Mrs. U.S. Grant; Sens. Hawley, Hale, Teller and Perkins; Mr. and Mrs. Chas. Holbrook; G.R. Holtzman; Gen F.H. Jones; Edward Largey; John B. McCarthy; John W. Mac Kay; Father Mc Nally; H.Z. Osborne; Mr. and Mrs. Requa; Ellsworth L. Rich; Roble Hall; John W. Shaw; John F. Sheehan; Philip W. Stanford; Jennie E. Weir; A.D. Wilder.
      Mar. 4, 1896 to Homer Bishop; John E "Geo" Bushnell (also unable to assist); F.S. Douty; Chas. Ed. Hodges (regret to invit.); John P. Irish; T. Kemp of Retail Merchants Protective Assn; C.O. Ziegenfuss. [includes a "general letter" - not signed]
      Mar. 5, 1896 to Cal. Girls "Cornell"; H.L. Dawes
    - 1896 Mar 6-Mar 13 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Mar. 6, 1896 to Belle Fielder (development of "God germ" at Stanford), Mr. and Mrs. Garniss, George E. Gray, Mr. and Mrs. Jerome Madden, Angela Morrison; Margaret Mary Wickham.
      Mar. 7, 1896 to Alexander Badlam, John C. Beatty, Charlotte Castle, Sarah B. Cooper, Aylett R. Cotton Jr., Day Frank, Mr. and Mrs. Hooker., L.C. Lane (misaddressed Dr. Mc Lean), Jas. Mc Cudden, P. Scanlon, Elena Atherton Selby, John Sexton, Jacob Shaen, Anna Shaw, Sisters of Mercy, Edward Taylor, Jho J. Valentine, Mrs. C.S. Walter, Clara Williams.
      Mar. 8, 1896 to Berton M. Palmer (his poem ought to be in the archives of University), J.A.B. Wilson.
      Mar. 9, 1896 to Samel [V.] Leech, Wm. F. Nichols
      Mar. 11, 1896 to Anne B. Dent, S, Isabelle Hubbard.
      Mar. 12, 1896 to Lucy Allabach, Jas. K. Anderson, Henry S. Foote, Mr. and Mrs. Jules Guthridge, Chas. E. Hall, Alex Hogg, Max Pracht (American Protective Tariff League).
      Mar. 13, 1896 to Jennie S. Catherwood, Mrs. E. S Dawes, Mr.and Mrs. R. F. Forrest, Julia Hamilton, Mrs. J.J. Owen, Thomas L. Powers., D.H. Temple.
    - 1896 Mar 14-Mar 17 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Mar. 14, 1896 to Mary P. Nimmo Balentine, Alma A. Park
      Mar. 15, 1896 to S. Goodenough of Calif. Universalist Convention (shall not hire any professor who would preach denominational theories of religion), Mrs. G.R. Knox, Helena McCarthy, John P. Neiman.
      Mar. 17, 1896 to Horace Davis, Mr. and Mrs. Foster, Edward M. Hulme (thanks for book of poems), Martin Kellogg, Mrs. S.J. Lippincott (Grace Greenwood), J.G. McCullough, Misses Patten, Mr. and Mrs. Wm. H. Ramsey, Gertrude Stanford, Mr. and Mrs. Stranahan, Andrew D. White., J. Lindley, Murray Young.
    - 1896 Mar 18-Mar 31 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Mar. 18, 1896 to Mrs. General. U.S. Grant, Anna Sterling Guthridge, Ellen T. Windom.
      Mar. 19, 1896 to [Winifred Black] (Annie Laurie), Samuel Colwood (Leland Stanford's religious beliefs), Mrs. Mattie S. Dayan, John J. Keane.
      Mar. 21, 1896 to Anna H. Clarkson (and personal).
      Mar. 23, 1896 to Mrs. Wm. E. Dodge, Sara A. Pryor.
      Mar. 25, 1896 to Mrs. E.W. Miller.
      Mar. 26, 1896 to Mary K. Matthews.
      Mar. 27, 1896 to Stephen J. Field.
      Mar. 31, 1896 to Louise S. Swan (Sen. Merrill, etc.)
      Mar. ?, 1896 to Jas. P. Brown, Maria Douglas, Sue V. Field, Isaias Hellman, Anna H. Shaw (tel. returned), Ellen F. Thompson, Zella Lentillian Wheeler.
    - 1896 Apr-Dec (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 1897 Jan-Aug (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 1897 Nov-Dec (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - 1898 Jan-May (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - 1898 Jun-Dec (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - 1899 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - 1900 Jan-Mar (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Tel to Thomas Hubbard; recommends Horace Platt as P. I. Co. representative, 17-Jan-00
      - LS to 0.L. Elliott. Regrets his article, women students on an equal basis., universal suffrage, limit on number of women students., 28-Jan-00
      - ALS to Mrs. Caswell; sends some religious books, 17-Feb-00
      - ALS to White Star Line. Deposit to secure stateroom No. 11 on S.S. Oceanic to Europe., March 16, 1900
    - 1900 Apr (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Tel to Thomas Hubbard; opposed to a partisan of one interest being treasurer of P. I. Co., 1-Apr-00
      - T.L. to Russell J. Wilson - retains his firm for next year; dismissed from Probate Court; P.I. Co. affairs., 8-Apr-00
      - ALS and cvr. (copies) to A.L. Rhodes and [S.] M. Bowman - requests them to witness her will., 9-Apr-00
      - ALS to May Hopkins; wants address of lady courier on Nile trip, 9-Apr-00
      - T.L. to S.F. Leib - names him Pres. Bd. of Trustees for next 2 years., 10-Apr-00
      - ALS and cvr. to Russell J. Wilson. Encloses check for special services., Apr 12, 1900 cvr for recpt for will-RJ Wilson Apr 13, 1900
      - AN to Hubbard and Crocker; willing N. T. Smith should be treasurer of P. I. Co., Apr-00